<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AMD Press Releases</title>
    <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Latest press releases from AMD]]></description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:04:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>AMD and HPE Expand Collaboration to Advance Open Rack-Scale AI Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1269/amd-and-hpe-expand-collaboration-to-advance-open-rack-scale-ai-infrastructure</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights HPE will be one of the first OEMs to adopt the AMD “Helios” architecture, an open, full-stack AI platform engineered for large-scale AI workloads. HPE will leverage purpose-built HPE Juniper Networking switches in “Helios” in collaboration with Broadcom, to deliver high-bandwidth, low-latency connectivity across massive AI clusters. AMD and HPE to power “Herder,” supercomputer built on the HPE Cray GX5000 platform with AMD Instinct™ MI430X GPUs and next generation AMD EPYC™ “Venice” CPUs, advancing HPC and Sovereign AI research across Europe. SANTA CLARA, Calif., Dec. 02, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Today, AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) announced an expanded collaboration with HPE to accelerate the next generation of open, scalable AI infrastructure built on AMD leadership compute technologies. HPE will become one of the first system providers to adopt the AMD “Helios” rack-scale AI architecture, which will integrate a purpose-built HPE Juniper Networking scale-up switch – in collaboration with Broadcom – and software for seamless, high-bandwidth connectivity over Ethernet. “Helios” combines AMD EPYC™ CPUs, AMD Instinct™ GPUs, AMD Pensando™ advanced networking and the AMD ROCm™ open software stack to deliver a cohesive platform optimized for performance, efficiency, and scalability. The system is engineered to simplify deployment of large-scale AI clusters, enabling faster time to solution and greater infrastructure flexibility across research, cloud, and enterprise environments. “HPE has been an exceptional long-term partner to AMD, working with us to redefine what is possible in high-performance computing,” said Dr. Lisa Su, Chair and CEO, AMD. “With ‘Helios’, we’re taking that collaboration further, bringing together the full stack of AMD compute technologies and HPE’s system innovation to deliver an open, rack-scale AI platform that drives new levels of efficiency, scalability, and breakthrough performance for our customers in the AI era.” “For more than a decade, HPE and AMD have pushed the boundaries of supercomputing, delivering multiple exascale-class systems and championing open standards that accelerate innovation,” said Antonio Neri, president and CEO at HPE. “With the introduction of the new AMD ‘Helios’ and our purpose-built HPE scale-up networking solution, we are providing our cloud service provider customers with faster deployments, greater flexibility, and reduced risk in how they scale AI computing in their businesses.” Advancing the Next Era of Industry Standard AI Infrastructure The AMD “Helios” rack-scale AI platform delivers up to 2.9 exaFLOPS of FP4 performance per rack using AMD Instinct MI455X GPUs, next-generation AMD EPYC “Venice” CPUs and AMD Pensando Vulcano NICs for scale-out networking, all unified through the open ROCm software ecosystem that enables flexibility and innovation across AI and HPC workloads. Built on the OCP Open Rack Wide design, “Helios” can help customers and partners streamline deployment timelines and deliver a scalable, flexible solution for demanding AI workloads. This has enabled HPE to integrate differentiated technologies for their customers, specifically a scale-up Ethernet switch and software designed for “Helios.” Developed in collaboration with Broadcom, the switch delivers optimized performance for AI workloads using the Ultra Accelerator Link over Ethernet (UALoE) standard, reinforcing the AMD commitment to open, standards-based technologies. HPE will offer the AMD “Helios” AI Rack-Scale Architecture worldwide in 2026. Powering Europe’s Next Generation of HPC and AI Innovation Herder, a new supercomputer for the High-Performance Computing Center Stuttgart (HLRS) in Germany, is powered by AMD Instinct™ MI430X GPUs and next-generation AMD EPYC™ “Venice” CPUs. Built on the HPE Cray Supercomputing GX5000 platform, Herder will offer world-class performance and efficiency for HPC and AI workloads at scale. The combination of the AMD leadership compute portfolio with HPE’s proven system design will create a powerful new tool for sovereign scientific discovery and industrial innovation for European researchers and enterprises. “The pairing of AMD Instinct MI430X GPUs and EPYC processors within HPE's GX5000 platform is a perfect solution for us at HLRS,” said Prof. Dr. Michael Resch, Director of HLRS. “Our scientific user community requires that we continue to support traditional applications of HPC for numerical simulation. At the same time, we are seeing growing interest in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Herder's system architecture will enable us to support both of these approaches, while also giving our users the ability to develop and benefit from new kinds of hybrid HPC/AI workflows. This platform will not only make it possible for our users to run larger, more powerful simulations that lead to exciting scientific discoveries, but also to develop more efficient computational methods that are only feasible with the capabilities that such next-generation hardware offers.” Delivery of Herder is scheduled for the second half of 2027 and it is expected to go into service by the end of 2027. Herder will replace HLRS's current flagship supercomputer, called Hunter. About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. Cautionary Statement This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) and Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) such as the features, functionality, performance, availability, timing and expected benefits of the AMD “Helios” rack-scale AI architecture, the HPE Cray GX5000 platform, and the expansion and expected benefits the AMD and HPE collaboration, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as “would,” “may,” “expects,” “believes,” “plans,” “intends,” “projects,” and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that these forward-looking statements are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and generally beyond the control of AMD and HPE, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: competitive markets in which AMD and HPE products are sold; market conditions of the industries in which AMD and HPE products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor and data center industries; loss of significant customers; the ability of third-party manufacturers and suppliers to deliver products and components on a timely basis and using competitive technologies; availability of essential materials and manufacturing processes; the ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields; the timely introduction of new products with expected features and performance levels; the impact of government regulations, including export controls and trade policies; and political, economic, or natural events that could affect operations. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s and HPE’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s and HPE’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. © 2025 Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. All rights reserved. AMD, the AMD Arrow logo, EPYC, AMD Instinct, ROCm, Pensando, and combinations thereof are trademarks of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. Juniper is a registered trademark of Juniper Networks, Inc. Hewlett Packard Enterprise and HPE are trademarks of Hewlett Packard Enterprise Company or its affiliates. Other names used herein are for informational purposes only and may be trademarks of their respective owners. Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1269/amd-and-hpe-expand-collaboration-to-advance-open-rack-scale-ai-infrastructure</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Powers Frontier AI Training for Zyphra</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1268/amd-powers-frontier-ai-training-for-zyphra</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights: Zyphra ZAYA1 becomes the first large-scale Mixture-of-Experts model trained entirely on AMD Instinct™ MI300X GPUs, AMD Pensando™ networking and ROCm open software. ZAYA1-base outperforms Llama-3-8B and OLMoE across multiple benchmarks and rivals the performance of Qwen3-4B and Gemma3-12B. Memory capacity of AMD Instinct MI300X helped Zyphra simplify its training capabilities, while achieving 10x faster model save times. SANTA CLARA, Calif., Nov. 24, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) announced that Zyphra has achieved a major milestone in large-scale AI model training with the development of ZAYA1, the first large-scale Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) foundation model trained using an AMD GPU and networking platform. Using AMD Instinct™ MI300X GPUs and AMD Pensando™ networking and enabled by the AMD ROCm™ open software stack, the achievement is detailed in a Zyphra technical report published today. Results from Zyphra show that the model delivers competitive or superior performance to leading open models across reasoning, mathematics, and coding benchmarks—demonstrating the scalability and efficiency of AMD Instinct GPUs for production-scale AI workloads. “AMD leadership in accelerated computing is empowering innovators like Zyphra to push the boundaries of what’s possible in AI,” said Emad Barsoum, corporate vice president of AI and engineering, Artificial Intelligence Group, AMD. “This milestone showcases the power and flexibility of AMD Instinct GPUs and Pensando networking for training complex, large-scale models.” “Efficiency has always been a core guiding principle at Zyphra. It shapes how we design model architectures, develop algorithms for training and inference, and choose the hardware with the best price-performance to deliver frontier intelligence to our customers,” said Krithik Puthalath, CEO of Zyphra. “ZAYA1 reflects this philosophy and we are thrilled to be the first company to demonstrate large-scale training on an AMD platform. Our results highlight the power of co-designing model architectures with silicon and systems, and we’re excited to deepen our collaboration with AMD and IBM as we build the next generation of advanced multimodal foundation models.” Efficient Training at Scale, Powered by AMD Instinct GPUs The AMD Instinct MI300X GPU’s 192 GB of high-bandwidth memory enabled efficient large-scale training, avoiding costly expert or tensor sharding, which reduced complexity and improving throughput across the full model stack. Zyphra also reported more than 10x faster model save times using AMD optimized distributed I/O, further enhancing training reliability and efficiency. With only a fraction of the active parameters, ZAYA1-Base (8.3B total, 760M active) matches or exceeds the performance of models such as Qwen3-4B (Alibaba), Gemma3-12B (Google), Llama-3-8B (Meta), and OLMoE. 1 Building on prior collaborative work, Zyphra worked closely with AMD and IBM to design and deploy a large-scale training cluster powered by AMD Instinct™ GPUs with AMD Pensando™ networking interconnect. The jointly engineered AMD and IBM system, announced earlier this quarter, combines AMD Instinct™ MI300X GPUs with IBM Cloud’s high-performance fabric and storage architecture, providing the foundation for ZAYA1’s large-scale pretraining. For further details on the results, read the Zyphra technical report , the Zyphra blog , and the AMD blog , for comprehensive overviews of the ZAYA1 model architecture, training methodology, and the AMD technologies that enabled its development. Supporting Resources Follow AMD on LinkedIn Follow AMD on Twitter Read more about AMD Instinct GPUs here Learn more about how AMD is advancing AI innovation at www.amd.com/aiapplications About AMD For more than 50 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics, and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses, and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work, and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , and X pages. Contact: David Szabados AMD Communications +1 408-472-2439 david.szabados@amd.com Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations +1 720-652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com _________________________ 1 Testing by Zyphra as of November 14, 2025, measuring the aggregate throughput of training iterations across the full Zyphra cluster measured in quadrillion floating point operations per second (PFLOPs). The workload was training a model comprised of a set of subsequent MLPs in BFLOAT16 across the full cluster of (128) compute nodes, each containing (8) AMD Instinct™ MI300X GPUs and (8) Pensando™ Pollara 400 Interconnects running a proprietary training stack created by Zyphra. Server manufacturers may vary configurations, yielding different results. Performance may vary based on use of the latest drivers and optimizations. This benchmark was collected with AMD ROCm 6.4. Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1268/amd-powers-frontier-ai-training-for-zyphra</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD and Eviden to Power Europe’s New Exascale Supercomputer, the First Based in France</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1267/amd-and-eviden-to-power-europes-new-exascale-supercomputer-the-first-based-in-france</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights The Alice Recoque supercomputer will expand Europe’s AI, scientific computing and research capabilities while ensuring energy efficiency and sovereignty. Alice Recoque will be powered by next-gen AMD EPYC CPUs and AMD Instinct MI430X GPUs to deliver more than one exaflop of HPL performance. SANTA CLARA, Calif. and PARIS, Nov. 18, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) and Eviden , the Atos Group product brand leading in advanced computing, announced their selection to build Alice Recoque, a next-generation supercomputer to support the need for high performance computing (HPC) and AI, serving as an AI Factory. Alice Recoque will be France’s first and Europe’s second Exascale supercomputer, led by Grand équipement national de calcul intensif (GENCI), operated by Commissariat à l'énergie atomique et aux énergies alternatives (CEA), and powered by next-generation AMD AI and HPC compute technologies. This project, representing an overall cost of 544 million euros, is funded by EuroHPC JU, with budget stemming from the Digital Europe Programme (DEP), and the Jules Verne Consortium, led by France through GENCI and CEA with the participation of Netherlands IT cooperation SURF and Greece with GRNET. "We are committed to enabling the next generation of innovation across AI and HPC,” said Dan McNamara, senior vice president and general manager, Compute & Enterprise AI, AMD. “The Alice Recoque supercomputer represents a major step forward for European sovereign AI, uniting national ambition, regional collaboration, and AMD’s high-performance and AI compute technologies. Through our continued collaboration with EuroHPC JU, the Jules Verne Consortium, and Eviden, we are proud to support Europe’s scientific and industrial leadership with a platform purpose-built for scale, efficiency and discovery." Emmanuel Le Roux, Group SVP, Global Head of Advanced Computing and AI, Eviden at Atos said, “ Alice Recoque represents another critical step toward Europe’s digital future, defined by a sovereignty, sustainability and scientific excellence. As a catalyst for scientific and industrial breakthroughs, from climate modeling and healthcare to advanced materials and AI innovation, it will empower researchers and industries across Europe. Born from a shared European vision, this AI Factory reflects on what we can achieve collectively toward a common goal. Eviden is fully dedicated to its success, bringing deep expertise, a collaborative spirit, and a long-term dedication to responsible technological leadership.” An AI-HPC Factory to Tackle Europe’s Most Pressing AI Challenges Alice Recoque will tackle Europe’s most pressing societal, scientific, and industrial challenges by combining large-scale simulations, data analysis, and AI. Alice Recoque covers the entire computing lifecycle, integrating cutting-edge hardware, advanced AI software and proven AI use cases to deliver scalable high-impact solutions. This comprehensive project is a live implementation of the strong collaboration and commitment from Eviden and AMD to accelerate research and industrialization of AI use cases, with a major investment in both human and technological resources. The Alice Recoque system is powered by next-gen AMD EPYC™ CPUs, codenamed “Venice,” AMD Instinct™ MI430X GPUs—a new MI400 Series accelerator engineered for sovereign AI and scientific computing— and AMD FPGAs, interconnected by Eviden’s network solution (BXI) into its newest BullSequana XH3500 platform, with DDN storage. This powerful system will enhance climate modeling, accelerate innovation in materials and energy, enable digital twins for personalized medicine, and support next-gen European AI models. Reaching Exascale with Fewer Resources and Reduced Energy Consumption Composed of 94 racks, Alice Recoque is expected to be one of the top supercomputers in Europe for double-precision HPC workloads. It will also offer exceptional memory performance enabling deeper insights, faster simulations, and more scientific breakthroughs. With 25 percent less racks and components than other Exascale systems and up to 50 percent better energy efficiency per GPU, Eviden’s architecture will enable Alice Recoque to deliver maximum performance at minimum cost and power, to meet Europe’s demanding green computing goals. Alice Recoque supports advanced AI data types from the AMD Instinct MI430X GPUs, including FP4 and FP8, providing leadership AI FLOPs. Each GPU integrates 432 GB of HBM4 memory and 19.6 TB/s of bandwidth which will enable Alice Recoque to deliver leadership capacity and throughput per GPU. Eviden’s integrated hardware and smart software, powered by AMD HPC and AI technologies, will deliver leading computing power with improved application workload energy efficiency. Real-time monitoring and energy optimization are enabled by Eviden’s Argos intelligent software, while its unique 5 th generation Direct Liquid Cooling technology uses warm water to cool 100% of all-in-one rack components, delivering efficiency and sustainability at scale. About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn and X pages. About Eviden Eviden is the Atos Group brand for hardware and software products with c. € 1 billion in revenue, operating in 36 countries and comprising four business units: advanced computing, cybersecurity products, mission-critical systems and vision AI. As a next-generation technology leader, Eviden offers a unique combination of hardware and software technologies for businesses, public sector and defense organizations and research institutions, helping them to create value out of their data. Bringing together more than 4,500 world-class talents and holding more than 2,100 patents, Eviden provides a strong portfolio of innovative and eco-efficient solutions in AI, computing, security, data and applications. About Atos Group Atos Group is a global leader in digital transformation with c. 67,000 employees and annual revenue of c. €10 billion, operating in 61 countries under two brands — Atos for services and Eviden for products. European number one in cybersecurity, cloud and high-performance computing, Atos Group is committed to a secure and decarbonized future and provides tailored AI-powered, end-to-end solutions for all industries. Atos Group is the brand under which Atos SE (Societas Europaea) operates. Atos SE is listed on Euronext Paris. The purpose of Atos Group is to help design the future of the information space. Its expertise and services support the development of knowledge, education and research in a multicultural approach and contribute to the development of scientific and technological excellence. Across the world, the Group enables its customers and employees, and members of societies at large to live, work and develop sustainably, in a safe and secure information space. CAUTIONARY STATEMENT This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) such as, AMD’s partnership with Eviden and Atos Group including plans, expected timing and expected benefits, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as "would," "may," "expects," "believes," "plans," "intends," "projects" and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and are generally beyond AMD's control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD’s ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD's ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD's products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD's ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD's reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD's reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors' support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD's supply chain; AMD's ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, import tariffs, trade protection measures and licensing requirements; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes and the revolving credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain key employees; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1267/amd-and-eviden-to-power-europes-new-exascale-supercomputer-the-first-based-in-france</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Unveils Strategy to Lead the $1 Trillion Compute Market and Accelerate Next Phase of Growth</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1266/amd-unveils-strategy-to-lead-the-1-trillion-compute-market-and-accelerate-next-phase-of-growth</link>
      <description><![CDATA[At Financial Analyst Day, AMD outlines long-term plan to expand data center and AI leadership with greater than 35% revenue CAGR and greater than $20 non-GAAP EPS target NEW YORK, Nov. 11, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Today at its Financial Analyst Day, AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) showcased its long-term strategy, leadership products and technology IP, underscoring the company’s momentum in driving accelerated growth and delivering long-term shareholder value. “AMD is entering a new era of growth fueled by our leadership technology roadmaps and accelerating AI momentum,” said Dr. Lisa Su, AMD chair and CEO. “With the broadest portfolio of products and our deepening strategic partnerships, AMD is uniquely positioned to lead the next generation of high-performance and AI computing. We see a tremendous opportunity ahead to deliver sustainable, industry-leading growth. We have never been better positioned.” Product Leadership and Momentum AMD highlighted its leadership across a broad portfolio of hardware, software and solutions to power the full spectrum of high-performance and AI compute. Data Center The AMD Instinct™ MI350 Series GPUs represent the fastest ramping product in company history, already deployed at scale by leading cloud providers including Oracle Cloud Infrastructure. The upcoming “Helios” systems with AMD Instinct MI450 Series GPUs are expected to deliver rack-scale performance leadership with industry leading memory capacity and scale-out bandwidth 1 beginning in the third quarter of 2026, followed by the MI500 Series, further extending AMD’s AI performance roadmap with a planned launch in 2027. AMD is accelerating server CPU revenue share gains across cloud and enterprise, on a path to market segment leadership, with the proven performance, scalability and efficiency of AMD EPYC™ processors. As AI adoption creates new demand for CPUs, next-generation “Venice” CPUs are designed to deliver the performance, density and energy efficiency to power AI and general-purpose infrastructure. AMD networking solutions power AI at scale, with Pensando™ Pollara and next-generation “Vulcano” AI NICs. Both deliver industry-leading bandwidth for scale-up and scale-out networking with true platform flexibility based on industry standards. Open Software AMD ROCm™ open software continues to gain developer momentum. AMD is delivering significant performance and feature enhancements with every release, and the number of ROCm software downloads has increased 10x year-over-year 2 . Client and Gaming AMD has expanded its AI PC portfolio 2.5x since 2024, with AMD Ryzen™ now powering more than 250 platforms across notebooks and desktops. Adopted by over half of the Fortune® 100, AMD Ryzen continues to drive commercial momentum 3 . AMD shared new details about its client processor roadmap, highlighting that AI PCs are expected to reach an AI performance inflection point with next-generation “Gorgon” and “Medusa” processors, delivering up to 10x gains since 2024 4 . Embedded AMD offers the industry’s broadest adaptive and embedded portfolio, spanning FPGAs, embedded x86 processors and semi-custom solutions. Since 2022, AMD has secured over $50 billion in design wins and is well positioned to accelerate AI-driven growth from cloud to edge. Semi-custom solutions and physical AI opportunities will expand long-term growth over the coming years. Technology Leadership AMD detailed how it will extend its chiplet, packaging, interconnect and open ecosystem innovation to drive accelerated AI performance and efficiency and introduced its 5 th Gen AMD Infinity Fabric technology, delivering scale-in, scale-up and scale-out leadership. AMD shared extended roadmaps across x86 CPUs, data center and gaming GPUs and NPUs. Long-Term Growth Targets AMD detailed a transformative long-term financial model based on its strategic financial priorities: accelerating revenue growth, delivering compelling profitability expansion and allocating capital to drive AI leadership. The company outlined the following growth targets for the next three to five years: At the company level, AMD expects to drive a greater than 35% revenue compound annual growth rate (CAGR), a non-GAAP operating margin greater than 35%, and non-GAAP earnings per share exceeding $20. Based on its leadership product portfolio, AMD expects to deliver a greater than 60% revenue CAGR for its data center business and greater than 10% revenue CAGR across its Embedded and Client and Gaming businesses. As AMD extends its multi-generational AMD EPYC CPU portfolio, it is positioned to lead the server market and expects to achieve more than 50% server CPU revenue market share. In data center AI, AMD aims to drive revenue CAGR of more than 80%, powered by strong customer momentum and next-generation AMD Instinct products and systems. Across Client and Gaming, AMD continues to strengthen its leadership with expanding enterprise adoption and a growing portfolio of AMD Ryzen processors. The company expects to exceed 40% client revenue market share while building on a base of more than one billion AMD-based gaming devices 5 and three generations of leadership consoles. AMD is also extending its leadership in adaptive computing, expects to exceed 70% revenue market share and plans to expand its Embedded segment opportunities to include growth from embedded x86 and semi-custom silicon markets. Supporting Resources Watch the Financial Analyst Day replay and access executive presentations here Read more about AMD data center leadership here Read more about AMD embedded business transformation here Read more about client and gaming momentum here Read more about AMD technology innovation here About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. CAUTIONARY STATEMENT This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) such as, AMD’s position to drive accelerated growth and deliver long-term value to its shareholders; AMD’s expected leadership in high-performance and AI computing; expectations of its financial plans and long-term financial model including compound annual growth rate, revenue market share, non-GAAP operating margin and non-GAAP earnings per share; AMD’s ability to achieve its strategic priorities; AMD’s expected growth and total addressable market; expected customer and market share opportunities; and the features, functionality, performance, availability, timing and expected benefits of future AMD products, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as "would," "may," "expects," "believes," "plans," "intends," "projects" and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and are generally beyond AMD's control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD’s ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD's ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD's products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD's ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD's reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD's reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors' support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD's supply chain; AMD's ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, import tariffs, trade protection measures and licensing requirements; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes and the revolving credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain key employees; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. NON-GAAP FINANCIAL MEASURES This press release contains forward-looking non-GAAP measures concerning AMD’s long-term financial model such as operating margin and earnings per share. These forward-looking non-GAAP measures are based on current expectations, assumptions and beliefs that involve numerous risks and uncertainties. Adjustments to arrive at the GAAP financial outlook and long-term financial model typically include stock-based compensation, amortization of acquired intangible assets, income tax provision, and other non-recurring items such as impairment charges and acquisition-related costs. A reconciliation to equivalent GAAP measures is not practicable at this time as the timing and impact of such adjustments are dependent on future events that are typically uncertain or outside of AMD's control. Such events may include unanticipated changes in AMD’s effective tax rate, unanticipated one-time charges related to asset impairments, unanticipated acquisition-related expenses, unanticipated gains, losses, and impairments, and other unanticipated non-recurring items not reflective of ongoing operations. All statements made in this press release are based on current expectations as of November 11, 2025, and assumptions and beliefs that involve numerous risks and uncertainties. AMD undertakes no intent or obligation to publicly update or revise its forward-looking statements made in this press release except as may be required by law. DISCLAIMER: The information contained herein is for informational purposes only and is subject to change without notice. While every precaution has been taken in the preparation of this document, it may contain technical inaccuracies, omissions and typographical errors, and AMD is under no obligation to update or otherwise correct this information. Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. makes no representations or warranties with respect to the accuracy or completeness of the contents of this document, and assumes no liability of any kind, including the implied warranties of noninfringement, merchantability or fitness for particular purposes, with respect to the operation or use of AMD hardware, software or other products described herein. No license, including implied or arising by estoppel, to any intellectual property rights is granted by this document. Terms and limitations applicable to the purchase or use of AMD products are as set forth in a signed agreement between the parties or in AMD's Standard Terms and Conditions of Sale. GD-18u. © 2025 Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. All rights reserved. AMD, the AMD Arrow logo, AMD Instinct, EPYC, Pensando, Radeon, ROCm, Ryzen, Versal, Xilinx, and combinations thereof are trademarks of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. CXL is a registered trademark of Compute Express Link Consortium, Inc. OpenAI is a trademark of OpenAI, Inc. PCIe® is a registered trademark of PCI-SIG Corporation. UCIE is a trademark of Universal Chiplet Interconnect Express, Inc. Ultra Accelerator Link and UALink are trademarks of the UALink Consortium. Other product names used in this publication are for identification purposes only and may be trademarks of their respective owners. Certain AMD technologies may require third-party enablement or activation. Supported features may vary by operating system. Please confirm with the system manufacturer for specific features. No technology or product can be completely secure. Fortune content is From Fortune Magazine. © 2025 Fortune Media IP Limited. All rights reserved. Used under license. Fortune is a registered trademark of Fortune Media IP Limited and is used under license. _______________________ 1 Calculations by AMD Performance Labs in June 2025, based on the projected memory capacity/ bandwidth and scale up/out bandwidth specifications of AMD Instinct™ MI455X 72xGPU “Helios” AI Rack vs. the publicly announced NVIDIA “Vera Rubin” 72xGPU “Oberon” Rack. Server manufacturers may vary configurations, yielding different results. MI350-045A 2 Based on AMD internal data as of November 2025 3 Fortune Magazine and Fortune Media (USA) Corporation are not affiliated with, and do not endorse products or services of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. o From Fortune Magazine. © 2025 Fortune Media IP Limited. All rights reserved. Used under license. 3 Projection based on AMD internal analysis and data as of Nov. 2025. Roadmap subject to change. 5 Based on AMD chip shipment figures, AMD has powered over 1 billion gaming devices with processors and graphics for desktop PCs, notebook PCs, and gaming consoles from 2008 to 2025. GD-250. Contact: Brandi Martina AMD Communications (512) 705-1720 Brandi.martina@amd.com Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations +1 720-652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1266/amd-unveils-strategy-to-lead-the-1-trillion-compute-market-and-accelerate-next-phase-of-growth</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Reports Third Quarter 2025 Financial Results</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1265/amd-reports-third-quarter-2025-financial-results</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Related Documents Earnings Webcast Audio Transcript Slide Presentation PDF Financial Tables PDF XLSX 10-Q HTML XBRL Zip SANTA CLARA, Calif., Nov. 04, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ:AMD) today announced financial results for the third quarter of 2025. Third quarter revenue was a record $9.2 billion, gross margin was 52%, operating income was $1.3 billion, net income was $1.2 billion and diluted earnings per share was $0.75. On a non-GAAP ( *) basis, gross margin was 54%, operating income was $2.2 billion, net income was $2 billion and diluted earnings per share was $1.20. Our third quarter results did not include any revenue from shipments of AMD Instinct™ MI308 GPU products to China. "We delivered an outstanding quarter, with record revenue and profitability reflecting broad based demand for our high-performance EPYC and Ryzen processors and Instinct AI accelerators," said Dr. Lisa Su, AMD chair and CEO. "Our record third quarter performance and strong fourth quarter guidance marks a clear step up in our growth trajectory as our expanding compute franchise and rapidly scaling data center AI business drive significant revenue and earnings growth." “We delivered record quarterly revenue of $9.2 billion, up 36% year-over-year, and generated record free cash flow, reflecting the strength of our leadership portfolio and disciplined execution,” said Jean Hu, AMD executive vice president, chief financial officer and treasurer. “Our continued investments in AI and high-performance computing are driving significant growth and position AMD to deliver long-term value creation.” GAAP Quarterly Financial Results Q3 2025 (1) Q3 2024 Y/Y Q2 2025 ( 2 ) Q/Q Revenue ($M) $9,246 $6,819 Up 36% $7,685 Up 20% Gross profit ($M) $4,780 $3,419 Up 40% $3,059 Up 56% Gross margin 52% 50% Up 2 ppts 40% Up 12 ppts Operating expenses ($M) $3,510 $2,695 Up 30% $3,193 Up 10% Operating income (loss) ($M) $1,270 $724 Up 75% $(134) Up 1,048% Operating margin 14% 11% Up 3 ppts (2)% Up 16 ppts Net income ($M) $1,243 $771 Up 61% $872 Up 43% Diluted earnings per share $0.75 $0.47 Up 60% $0.54 Up 39% Non-GAAP(*) Quarterly Financial Results Q3 2025 ( 1 ) Q3 2024 Y/Y Q2 2025 ( 2 ) Q/Q Revenue ($M) $9,246 $6,819 Up 36% $7,685 Up 20% Gross profit ($M) $4,992 $3,657 Up 37% $3,326 Up 50% Gross margin 54% 54% Flat 43% Up 11 ppts Operating expenses ($M) $2,754 $1,942 Up 42% $2,429 Up 13% Operating income ($M) $2,238 $1,715 Up 30% $897 Up 149% Operating margin 24% 25% Down 1 ppt 12% Up 12 ppts Net income ($M) $1,965 $1,504 Up 31% $781 Up 152% Diluted earnings per share $1.20 $0.92 Up 30% $0.48 Up 150% (1) Third quarter of 2025 results do not include any revenue from shipments of the AMD Instinct™ MI308 GPU products to China. (2) Second quarter of 2025 results included $800 million in inventory and related charges as a result of the U.S. Government's export control on AMD Instinct™ MI308 data center GPU products. Excluding these charges, non-GAAP gross margin for the second quarter of 2025 would have been approximately 54%. Segment Summary Data Center segment revenue was $4.3 billion, up 22% year-over-year primarily driven by strong demand for 5 th Gen AMD EPYC™ processors and AMD Instinct MI350 Series GPUs. Client and Gaming segment revenue was $4 billion, up 73% year-over-year. Client revenue was a record $2.8 billion, up 46% year-over-year primarily driven by record sales of Ryzen™ processors and a richer product mix. Gaming revenue was $1.3 billion, up 181% year-over-year driven by higher semi-custom revenue and strong demand for Radeon™ gaming GPUs. Embedded segment revenue was $857 million, down 8% year-over-year. Recent PR Highlights Customer momentum for AMD AI platforms is accelerating: OpenAI and AMD announced a strategic partnership where AMD will be a core preferred partner to deploy 6 gigawatts of AMD GPUs to power OpenAI’s next generation AI infrastructure, with the first 1-gigawatt deployment of AMD Instinct MI450 GPUs set to begin in the second half of 2026. Oracle and AMD announced that Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) will offer the first publicly available AI supercluster powered by the AMD “Helios” rack design with AMD Instinct MI450 GPUs, EPYC “Venice” CPUs and Pensando™ “Vulcano” networking, with an initial deployment of 50,000 GPUs starting in Q3 2026. AMD unveiled its “Helios” rack scale design that supports the new Open Rack Wide specification introduced by Meta at Open Compute Project Global Summit. Cisco and AMD announced an expanded collaboration with G42 to deploy a large-scale AI cluster powered by AMD Instinct MI355X GPUs to advance secure AI infrastructure across UAE. IBM and AMD announced a multi-year collaboration to provide Zyphra with advanced AI infrastructure, leveraging a large cluster of AMD Instinct MI350X GPUs to power next-generation multimodal AI models. Cohere and AMD expanded their collaboration, bringing AMD Instinct GPU-powered infrastructure to Cohere’s full suite of enterprise AI offerings. Vultr announced the global availability of AMD Instinct MI355X GPUs across its cloud platform. DigitalOcean expanded its AMD-based cloud offerings to support a broader range of AI workloads with AMD Instinct MI325X GPUs available now and AMD Instinct MI350X GPUs available later this year. AMD and Tech Mahindra announced a collaboration to bring AMD Instinct GPUs and AMD EPYC processors to the Cloud BlazeTech enterprise AI solution. AMD and the U.S. Department of Energy announced two new next-generation supercomputers: The Lux AI supercomputer, powered by AMD Instinct MI355X GPUs, AMD EPYC CPUs and AMD Pensando advanced networking technologies, will be the first U.S. AI factory supercomputer. The Discovery supercomputer, expected to be delivered in 2028, will be based on next-gen AMD EPYC CPUs, codenamed “Venice,” and AMD Instinct MI430X GPUs, a new MI400 Series accelerator designed for sovereign AI and scientific computing. AMD released ROCm™ 7 software, boosting training and inference performance and expanding enterprise tools for infrastructure management and deployment. AMD announced the completion of the divestiture of the ZT Systems data center infrastructure manufacturing business to Sanmina. AMD partners expanded their cloud offerings based on AMD EPYC processors to meet growing compute demand for enterprise and AI workloads: AWS announced the availability of Amazon EC2 M8a general-purpose instance powered by 5 th Gen AMD EPYC processors, delivering up to 30% higher performance than the previous generation. Oracle announced next-gen Compute Cloud@Customer X11 and Private Cloud Appliance X11 platforms powered by 5 th Gen AMD EPYC processors. IBM and AMD announced plans to combine quantum computers and high-performance compute to drive scalable, open-source next-generation computing architectures. AMD delivered new capabilities for the most demanding PC and gaming workloads, including: The AMD Ryzen™ Threadripper™ 9000WX and Ryzen Threadripper PRO 9000X Series processors , delivering unmatched multi-core performance and platform capabilities for creators, enthusiasts and professionals. AMD FSR 4 , a ML-based upscaling technology that enhances frame rates and visuals, saw rapid adoption with supported games doubling since launch to over 85. AMD expanded its x86 embedded processor portfolio, including: The AMD EPYC Embedded 4005 series processors , built to deliver performance, optimized system costs and extended deployment lifecycles in network security appliances and entry-level industrial edge servers. The AMD Ryzen Embedded 9000 processors delivering exceptional performance-per-watt, low latency, and the long-term stability for industrial PCs, automation systems and machine vision applications. Current Outlook AMD’s outlook statements are based on current expectations. The following statements are forward-looking and actual results could differ materially depending on market conditions and the factors set forth under “Cautionary Statement” below. For the fourth quarter of 2025, AMD expects revenue to be approximately $9.6 billion, plus or minus $300 million. At the mid-point of the revenue range, this represents year-over-year growth of approximately 25% and sequential growth of approximately 4%. Non-GAAP gross margin is expected to be approximately 54.5%. Our current outlook does not include any revenue from AMD Instinct MI308 shipments to China. AMD Teleconference AMD will hold a conference call at 2:00 p.m. PT (5:00 p.m. ET) today to discuss its third quarter 2025 financial results. AMD will provide a real-time audio broadcast of the teleconference on the Investor Relations page of its website at www.amd.com . RECONCILIATION OF GAAP TO NON-GAAP FINANCIAL MEASURES (in millions, except per share data) (Unaudited) Three Months Ended September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 GAAP gross profit $ 4,780 $ 3,059 $ 3,419 GAAP gross margin 52 % 40 % 50 % Stock-based compensation 7 6 5 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 260 260 233 Acquisition-related and other costs (1) — 1 — Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer (2) (67 ) — — Loss contingency on legal matter 12 — — Non-GAAP gross profit $ 4,992 $ 3,326 $ 3,657 Non-GAAP gross margin 54 % 43 % 54 % GAAP operating expenses (3) $ 3,510 $ 3,193 $ 2,695 GAAP operating expenses/revenue % 38 % 42 % 40 % Stock-based compensation 412 363 346 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 302 308 352 Acquisition-related and other costs (1) 42 93 55 Non-GAAP operating expenses (3) $ 2,754 $ 2,429 $ 1,942 Non-GAAP operating expenses/revenue % 30 % 32 % 28 % GAAP operating income (loss) $ 1,270 $ (134 ) $ 724 GAAP operating margin 14 % (2) % 11 % Stock-based compensation 419 369 351 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 562 568 585 Acquisition-related and other costs (1) 42 94 55 Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer (2) (67 ) — — Loss contingency on legal matter 12 — — Non-GAAP operating income $ 2,238 $ 897 $ 1,715 Non-GAAP operating margin 24 % 12 % 25 % Three Months Ended September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 GAAP net income / earnings per share $ 1,243 $ 0.75 $ 872 $ 0.54 $ 771 $ 0.47 Stock-based compensation 419 0.26 369 0.23 351 0.21 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 562 0.34 568 0.35 585 0.36 Acquisition-related and other costs (1) 43 0.03 96 0.05 56 0.03 Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer (2) (67 ) (0.04 ) — — — — Loss contingency on legal matter 12 0.01 — — — — (Gains) losses on equity investments, net (26 ) (0.02 ) (61 ) (0.04 ) (1 ) — Equity income in investee (10 ) — (8 ) — (7 ) — Release of reserves for uncertain tax positions (4) — — (853 ) (0.52 ) — — Income tax provision (140 ) (0.09 ) (98 ) (0.06 ) (251 ) (0.15 ) Income from discontinued operations, net of tax (5) (71 ) (0.04 ) (104 ) (0.07 ) — — Non-GAAP net income / earnings per share $ 1,965 $ 1.20 $ 781 $ 0.48 $ 1,504 $ 0.92 (1) Acquisition-related and other costs primarily include transaction costs, purchase price fair value adjustments for inventory, certain compensation charges, and workforce rebalancing charges. (2) Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer is related to losses due to an incident at a third-party contract manufacturing facility in Q1’24 and the corresponding recovery. (3) Effective first quarter of 2025, licensing gain is reclassified against Marketing, general and administrative expenses as the amounts were immaterial. (4) Release of reserves for uncertain tax positions pertains to the reasonable cause relief related to dual consolidated losses approved by IRS in Q2'25. (5) Income from discontinued operations is related to ZT Systems' manufacturing business which is classified as held-for-sale. RECONCILIATION OF GAAP TO ADJUSTED NON-GAAP FINANCIAL MEASURES (Millions) (Unaudited) Three Months Ended June 28, 2025 GAAP gross profit $ 3,059 GAAP gross margin 40 % Stock-based compensation, amortization of acquisition-related intangibles, acquisition-related and other costs 267 Inventory and related charges associated with U.S. export restrictions 800 Non-GAAP gross profit (as adjusted to exclude inventory and related charges associated with U.S. export restrictions) $ 4,126 Non-GAAP gross margin (as adjusted to exclude inventory and related charges associated with U.S. export restrictions) 54 % About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn and X pages. Cautionary Statement This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) such as, the features, functionality, performance, availability, timing and expected benefits of future AMD products; AMD’s growth trajectory; the expected revenue and earnings growth from AMD’s compute franchise and AI business; AMD’s ability to drive significant growth and position itself to deliver long-term value creation based on continued investments in AI and high-performance computing; the strategic partnership with OpenAI and the deployment of six gigawatts of AMD Instinct™ GPUs and timing thereof; the strategic partnership with Oracle and the deployment of 50,000 GPUs and timing thereof; and AMD’s expected fourth quarter 2025 financial outlook, including revenue and non-GAAP gross margin, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as "would," "may," "expects," "believes," "plans," "intends," "projects" and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and are generally beyond AMD’s control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, import tariffs, trade protection measures, and licensing requirements; competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD's ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD's ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD's products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD's ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD's reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD's reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors' support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD's supply chain; AMD's ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes and the revolving credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain key employees; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. (*) In this earnings press release, in addition to GAAP financial results, AMD has provided non-GAAP financial measures including non-GAAP gross profit, non-GAAP gross margin, non-GAAP operating expenses, non-GAAP operating expenses/revenue percent, non-GAAP operating income, non-GAAP operating margin, non-GAAP net income and non-GAAP diluted earnings per share. AMD uses a normalized tax rate in its computation of the non-GAAP income tax provision to provide better consistency across the reporting periods. For fiscal 2025, AMD used a non-GAAP tax rate of 13%, which excludes the tax impact of pre-tax non-GAAP adjustments. Additionally, AMD has provided an adjusted non-GAAP gross profit and gross margin for the second quarter of 2025 which excluded the inventory and related charges associated with U.S. export restrictions. AMD also provides adjusted EBITDA, free cash flow and free cash flow margin as supplemental non-GAAP measures of its performance. These items are defined in the footnotes to the selected corporate data tables provided at the end of this earnings press release. AMD is providing these financial measures because it believes this non-GAAP presentation makes it easier for investors to compare its operating results for current and historical periods and also because AMD believes it assists investors in comparing AMD’s performance across reporting periods on a consistent basis by excluding items that it does not believe are indicative of its core operating performance and for the other reasons described in the footnotes to the selected data tables. The non-GAAP financial measures disclosed in this earnings press release should be viewed in addition to and not as a substitute for or superior to AMD’s reported results prepared in accordance with GAAP and should be read only in conjunction with AMD’s Consolidated Financial Statements prepared in accordance with GAAP. These non-GAAP financial measures referenced are reconciled to their most directly comparable GAAP financial measures in the data tables in this earnings press release. This earnings press release also contains forward-looking non-GAAP gross margin concerning AMD’s financial outlook, which is based on current expectations as of November 4, 2025, and assumptions and beliefs that involve numerous risks and uncertainties. Adjustments to arrive at the GAAP gross margin outlook typically include stock-based compensation, amortization of acquired intangible assets and acquisition-related and other costs. The timing and impact of such adjustments are dependent on future events that are typically uncertain or outside of AMD's control, therefore, a reconciliation to equivalent GAAP measures is not practicable at this time. AMD undertakes no intent or obligation to publicly update or revise its outlook statements as a result of new information, future events or otherwise, except as may be required by law. ©2025 Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. All rights reserved. AMD, the AMD Arrow logo, AMD Instinct, EPYC, Pensando, Radeon, ROCm, Ryzen, Spartan, Threadripper, Ultrascale+, Versal and combinations thereof, are trademarks of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. ADVANCED MICRO DEVICES, INC. CONDENSED CONSOLIDATED STATEMENTS OF OPERATIONS (Millions except per share amounts and percentages) (Unaudited) Three Months Ended Nine Months Ended September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 Net revenue $ 9,246 $ 7,685 $ 6,819 $ 24,369 $ 18,127 Cost of sales 4,206 4,366 3,167 12,023 8,590 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 260 260 233 771 694 Total cost of sales 4,466 4,626 3,400 12,794 9,284 Gross profit 4,780 3,059 3,419 11,575 8,843 Gross margin 52 % 40 % 50 % 47 % 49 % Research and development 2,139 1,894 1,636 5,761 4,744 Marketing, general and administrative 1,069 991 707 2,946 1,954 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 302 308 352 926 1,116 Total operating expenses 3,510 3,193 2,695 9,633 7,814 Operating income (loss) 1,270 (134 ) 724 1,942 1,029 Interest expense (37 ) (38 ) (23 ) (95 ) (73 ) Other income (expense), net 82 98 36 219 144 Income from continuing operations before income taxes and equity income 1,315 (74 ) 737 2,066 1,100 Income tax provision (benefit) 153 (834 ) (27 ) (558 ) (38 ) Equity income in investee 10 8 7 25 21 Income from continuing operations, net of tax 1,172 768 771 2,649 1,159 Income from discontinued operations, net of tax 71 104 — 175 — Net income $ 1,243 $ 872 $ 771 $ 2,824 $ 1,159 Earnings per share: Earnings from continuing operations - basic $ 0.72 $ 0.47 $ 0.48 $ 1.63 $ 0.72 Earnings from discontinued operations - basic $ 0.04 $ 0.07 $ — $ 0.11 $ — Basic earnings per share $ 0.76 $ 0.54 $ 0.48 $ 1.74 $ 0.72 Earnings from continuing operations - diluted $ 0.71 $ 0.47 $ 0.47 $ 1.62 $ 0.71 Earnings from discontinued operations - diluted $ 0.04 $ 0.07 $ — $ 0.11 $ — Diluted earnings per share $ 0.75 $ 0.54 $ 0.47 $ 1.73 $ 0.71 Shares used in per share calculation Basic 1,626 1,623 1,620 1,623 1,619 Diluted 1,641 1,630 1,636 1,632 1,638 ADVANCED MICRO DEVICES, INC. CONDENSED CONSOLIDATED BALANCE SHEETS (Millions) September 27, 2025 December 28, 2024 (Unaudited) ASSETS Current assets: Cash and cash equivalents $ 4,808 $ 3,787 Short-term investments 2,435 1,345 Accounts receivable, net 6,201 6,192 Inventories 7,313 5,734 Assets held for sale 3,990 — Prepaid expenses and other current assets 2,253 1,991 Total current assets 27,000 19,049 Property and equipment, net 2,205 1,802 Goodwill 25,083 24,839 Acquisition-related intangibles, net 17,250 18,930 Deferred tax assets 633 688 Other non-current assets 4,720 3,918 Total Assets $ 76,891 $ 69,226 LIABILITIES AND STOCKHOLDERS' EQUITY Current liabilities: Accounts payable $ 3,483 $ 2,466 Accrued liabilities 5,112 4,260 Current portion of long-term debt, net 873 — Liabilities held for sale 1,908 — Other current liabilities 324 555 Total current liabilities 11,700 7,281 Long-term debt 2,347 1,721 Long-term operating lease liabilities 650 491 Deferred tax liabilities 326 349 Other long-term liabilities 1,078 1,816 Stockholders' equity: Capital stock: Common stock, par value $0.01 17 17 Additional paid-in capital 62,657 61,362 Treasury stock, at cost (7,059 ) (6,106 ) Retained earnings 5,188 2,364 Accumulated other comprehensive loss (13 ) (69 ) Total stockholders' equity 60,790 57,568 Total Liabilities and Stockholders' Equity $ 76,891 $ 69,226 ADVANCED MICRO DEVICES, INC. CONDENSED CONSOLIDATED STATEMENTS OF CASH FLOWS (Millions) (Unaudited) Three Months Ended Nine Months Ended September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 Cash flows from operating activities: Net income $ 1,243 $ 771 $ 2,824 $ 1,159 Income from discontinued operations, net of tax (71 ) — (175 ) — Adjustments to reconcile net income to net cash provided by operating activities: Depreciation and amortization 192 171 556 499 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 562 585 1,697 1,810 Stock-based compensation 419 351 1,152 1,068 Deferred income taxes 218 (607 ) 18 (863 ) Release of reserves for uncertain tax positions — — (853 ) — Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer (67 ) — (67 ) 65 Other — 17 29 32 Changes in operating assets and liabilities: Accounts receivable, net (1,085 ) (2,213 ) (7 ) (1,961 ) Inventories (636 ) (386 ) (1,579 ) (1,096 ) Prepaid expenses and current assets 118 703 (259 ) (171 ) Accounts payable 451 873 998 574 Accrued and other liabilities 444 363 (145 ) 626 Net cash provided by operating activities of continuing operations 1,788 628 4,189 1,742 Net cash provided by operating activities of discontinued operations 371 — 920 — Net cash flows provided by operations 2,159 628 5,109 1,742 Cash flows from investing activities: Purchases of property and equipment (258 ) (132 ) (752 ) (428 ) Purchases of short-term investments (1,314 ) (142 ) (2,110 ) (707 ) Proceeds from maturity of short-term investments 299 149 982 1,351 Proceeds from sale of short-term investments 18 589 66 591 Purchases of strategic investments (74 ) (37 ) (432 ) (131 ) Acquisitions, net of cash acquired — (548 ) (1,716 ) (548 ) Other — (17 ) — (15 ) Net cash (used in) provided by investing activities of continuing operations (1,329 ) (138 ) (3,962 ) 113 Net cash (used in) investing activities of discontinued operations (8 ) — (30 ) — Net cash flows (used in) provided by investing activities (1,337 ) (138 ) (3,992 ) 113 Cash flows from financing activities: Proceeds from debt and commercial paper issuance, net of issuance costs — — 2,441 — Repayment of debt and commercial paper — — (950 ) (750 ) Proceeds from sales of common stock through employee equity plans 10 4 169 152 Repurchases of common stock (89 ) (250 ) (1,316 ) (606 ) Stock repurchases for tax withholding on employee equity plans (371 ) (460 ) (447 ) (686 ) Other — — — (1 ) Net cash (used in) provided by financing activities of continuing operations (450 ) (706 ) (103 ) (1,891 ) Net (decrease) increase in cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash 372 (216 ) 1,014 (36 ) Cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash at beginning of period 4,453 4,113 3,811 3,933 Cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash at end of period $ 4,825 $ 3,897 $ 4,825 $ 3,897 Reconciliation of cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash Cash and cash equivalents $ 4,808 $ 3,897 $ 4,808 $ 3,897 Restricted cash included in Prepaid expenses and other current assets 17 — 17 — Cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash at end of period $ 4,825 $ 3,897 $ 4,825 $ 3,897 ADVANCED MICRO DEVICES, INC. SELECTED CORPORATE DATA (Millions) (Unaudited) Three Months Ended Nine Months Ended September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 Segment and Disaggregated Revenue Information ( 1) Net Revenue: Data Center Segment $ 4,341 $ 3,240 $ 3,549 $ 11,255 $ 8,720 Client and Gaming Segment Client 2,750 2,499 1,881 7,543 4,741 Gaming 1,298 1,122 462 3,067 2,032 Total Client and Gaming 4,048 3,621 2,343 10,610 6,773 Embedded Segment 857 824 927 2,504 2,634 Total net revenue $ 9,246 $ 7,685 $ 6,819 $ 24,369 $ 18,127 Operating Income (Loss): Data Center Segment $ 1,074 $ (155 ) $ 1,041 $ 1,851 $ 2,325 Client and Gaming Segment 867 767 288 2,130 691 Embedded Segment 283 275 372 886 1,059 All other (954 ) (1,021 ) (977 ) (2,925 ) (3,046 ) Total operating income (loss) $ 1,270 $ (134 ) $ 724 $ 1,942 $ 1,029 Other Data Capital expenditures $ 258 $ 282 $ 132 $ 752 $ 428 Adjusted EBITDA (2) $ 2,431 $ 1,088 $ 1,887 $ 5,473 $ 4,612 Cash, cash equivalents and short-term investments $ 7,243 $ 5,867 $ 4,544 $ 7,243 $ 4,544 Free cash flow (3) $ 1,530 $ 1,180 $ 496 $ 3,437 $ 1,314 Total assets $ 76,891 $ 74,820 $ 69,636 $ 76,891 $ 69,636 Total debt $ 3,220 $ 3,218 $ 1,720 $ 3,220 $ 1,720 (1) The Company operates as three operating segments, Data Center, Client and Gaming, and Embedded segments. The Data Center segment primarily includes Artificial Intelligence (AI) accelerators, server microprocessors (CPUs), graphics processing units (GPUs), accelerated processing units (APUs), data processing units (DPUs), Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs), Smart Network Interface Cards (SmartNICs) and Adaptive System-on-Chip (SoC) products for data centers. The Client and Gaming segment primarily includes CPUs, APUs, and chipsets for desktops and notebooks, and discrete GPUs, semi-custom SoC products and development services. The Embedded segment primarily includes embedded CPUs, GPUs, APUs, FPGAs, System on Modules (SOMs), and Adaptive SoC products. From time to time, the Company may also sell or license portions of its IP portfolio. All Other category primarily includes certain expenses and credits that are not allocated to any of the operating segments, such as amortization of acquisition-related intangibles, employee stock-based compensation expense, acquisition-related and other costs, inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer and restructuring charges. (2) Reconciliation of GAAP Net Income to Adjusted EBITDA Three Months Ended Nine Months Ended (Millions) (Unaudited) September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 GAAP net income $ 1,243 $ 872 $ 771 $ 2,824 $ 1,159 Interest expense 37 38 23 95 73 Other (income) expense, net (82 ) (98 ) (36 ) (219 ) (144 ) Income tax provision (benefit) 153 (834 ) (27 ) (558 ) (38 ) Equity income in investee (10 ) (8 ) (7 ) (25 ) (21 ) Stock-based compensation 419 369 351 1,152 1,068 Depreciation and amortization 192 189 171 556 499 Amortization of acquisition-related intangibles 562 568 585 1,697 1,810 Acquisition-related and other costs 43 96 56 181 141 Inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer (67 ) — — (67 ) 65 Loss contingency on legal matter 12 — — 12 — Income from discontinued operations, net of tax (71 ) (104 ) — (175 ) — Adjusted EBITDA $ 2,431 $ 1,088 $ 1,887 $ 5,473 $ 4,612 The Company presents “Adjusted EBITDA” as a supplemental measure of its performance. Adjusted EBITDA for the Company is determined by adjusting GAAP net income for interest expense, other (income) expense, net, income tax provision (benefit), equity income in investee, stock-based compensation, depreciation and amortization expense, amortization of acquisition-related intangibles, acquisition-related and other costs, inventory loss at (recovery from) contract manufacturer, loss contingency on legal matter, and income from discontinued operations, net of tax. The Company calculates and presents Adjusted EBITDA because management believes it is of importance to investors and lenders in relation to its overall capital structure and its ability to borrow additional funds. In addition, the Company presents Adjusted EBITDA because it believes this measure assists investors in comparing its performance across reporting periods on a consistent basis by excluding items that the Company does not believe are indicative of its core operating performance. The Company’s calculation of Adjusted EBITDA may or may not be consistent with the calculation of this measure by other companies in the same industry. Investors should not view Adjusted EBITDA as an alternative to the GAAP operating measure of net income or GAAP liquidity measures of cash flows from operating, investing and financing activities. In addition, Adjusted EBITDA does not take into account changes in certain assets and liabilities that can affect cash flows. (3) Reconciliation of GAAP Net Cash Provided by Operating Activities of Continuing Operations to Free Cash Flow Three Months Ended Nine Months Ended (Millions except percentages) (Unaudited) September 27, 2025 June 28, 2025 September 28, 2024 September 27, 2025 September 28, 2024 GAAP net cash provided by operating activities of continuing operations $ 1,788 $ 1,462 $ 628 $ 4,189 $ 1,742 Operating cash flow margin % from continuing operations 19 % 19 % 9 % 17 % 10 % Purchases of property and equipment (258 ) (282 ) (132 ) (752 ) (428 ) Free cash flow $ 1,530 $ 1,180 $ 496 $ 3,437 $ 1,314 Free cash flow margin % 17 % 15 % 7 % 14 % 7 % The Company also presents free cash flow as a supplemental Non-GAAP measure of its performance. Free cash flow is determined by adjusting GAAP net cash provided by operating activities of continuing operations for capital expenditures, and free cash flow margin % is free cash flow expressed as a percentage of the Company's net revenue. The Company calculates and communicates free cash flow in the financial earnings press release because management believes it is of importance to investors to understand the nature of these cash flows. The Company’s calculation of free cash flow may or may not be consistent with the calculation of this measure by other companies in the same industry. Investors should not view free cash flow as an alternative to GAAP liquidity measures of cash flows from operating activities. Media Contact: Phil Hughes AMD Communications 512-865-9697 phil.hughes@amd.com Investor Contact: Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations 720-652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1265/amd-reports-third-quarter-2025-financial-results</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Powers U.S. Sovereign AI Factory Supercomputers, Accelerating an Open American AI Stack</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1264/amd-powers-u-s-sovereign-ai-factory-supercomputers-accelerating-an-open-american-ai-stack</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights The Lux AI supercomputer, powered by AMD and housed at Oak Ridge National Labs, will be the first dedicated U.S. AI factory for science and will be deployed in early 2026. AMD will power the next-generation supercomputer at Oak Ridge National Labs, called Discovery – which will advance U.S. AI and scientific research at massive scale. Together, Lux and Discovery, directly support the U.S. AI Action Plan by accelerating AI-enabled science, strengthening national competitiveness, and enabling secure, sovereign AI infrastructure for the nation. SANTA CLARA, Calif., Oct. 27, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) and the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) today announced two next-generation systems at Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) designed to expand America’s leadership in artificial intelligence (AI) and high-performance computing (HPC), the Lux AI supercomputer and the Discovery supercomputer. Discovery and Lux will be DOE flagship supercomputers designed to drive breakthroughs in science, energy, and national security. Both systems directly support the U.S. AI Action Plan by accelerating AI-enabled science, strengthening national competitiveness, and advancing secure, sovereign AI infrastructure for the nation. Together with the U.S. government, ORNL and industry partners, AMD will deliver advanced computing platforms that help national researchers, agencies, and innovators tackle pressing challenges in energy, medicine, health, and national security. When fully deployed, the Lux and Discovery systems will represent a combined $1billion investment of private and public funding which will enable the DOE to build a secure, federated and standards-based infrastructure for sovereign U.S. AI and science. “We are proud and honored to partner with the Department of Energy and Oak Ridge National Laboratory to accelerate America’s foundation for science and innovation,” said Dr. Lisa Su, chair and CEO, AMD. “Discovery and Lux will leverage AMD’s high-performance and AI computing technologies to advance the most critical U.S. research priorities in science, energy, and medicine – demonstrating the power of public-private partnership at their best.” The Lux AI supercomputer – co-developed by ORNL, AMD, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) and HPE and powered by AMD Instinct™ MI355X GPUs, AMD EPYC™ CPUs and AMD Pensando™ advanced networking technologies – will be deployed in early 2026, making it the first US AI Factory supercomputer setting the stage for novel public and private partnerships. The Lux system will address the immediate needs to expand the DOE’s AI leadership and accelerate progress and innovation in the areas of AI, energy research, materials, medicine and advanced manufacturing. The Discovery supercomputer deepens the collaboration between the DOE, ORNL, HPE and AMD. At the heart of Discovery are next-gen AMD EPYC CPUs, codenamed “Venice,” and AMD Instinct™ MI430X GPUs— a new MI400 Series accelerator engineered specifically for sovereign AI and scientific computing. MI430X extends the leadership AMD architecture for AI and HPC, enabling the U.S. to train, simulate, and deploy AI models on domestically built systems that protect national data and scientific competitiveness. “Winning the AI race requires new and creative partnerships that will bring together the brightest minds and industries American technology and science has to offer,” said U.S. Secretary of Energy Chris Wright. “That’s why the Trump administration is announcing the first example of a new commonsense approach to computing partnerships with Lux. We are also announcing, as part of a competitive procurement process, Discovery. Working with AMD and HPE, we’re bringing new capacity online faster than ever before, turning shared innovation into national strength, and proving that America leads when private-public partners build together.” “The Discovery system will drive scientific innovation faster and farther than ever before,” said ORNL Director Stephen Streiffer. “ORNL’s leadership in supercomputing has dramatically shortened researchers’ time from problem to solution across a host of fields and industries. With Discovery, the integration of high-performance computing and AI promises breakthroughs at the accelerated speed and scale necessary for continued U.S. leadership in an increasingly competitive global environment.” “We are proud that the partnership between HPE and AMD is at the forefront of advancing the next generation of supercomputing in the AI era for Oak Ridge National Laboratory,” said Antonio Neri, president and CEO at HPE. “HPE’s newest supercomputing solutions harness converged AI and HPC architectures, enabling the lab to achieve unprecedented productivity and scale. This collaboration also reinforces American leadership in applying AI to science, energy and national security.” “Oracle is honored to work alongside the Department of Energy to help drive breakthroughs in science, energy, and national security,” said Mahesh Thiagarajan, executive vice president, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure. “Oracle will deliver sovereign, high-performance AI infrastructure that will support the co-development of the Lux AI cluster.” Lux AI Supercomputer: Advancing U.S. AI Leadership Lux at ORNL is the nation’s first dedicated AI Factory for science, energy, and national security—purpose-built to train, fine-tune, and deploy AI foundation models that will accelerate discovery and engineering innovation. Lux is designed to accelerate AI-driven science through its advanced architecture, optimized for data-intensive and model-centric workloads. As a critical resource for the DOE and the National Laboratory system, Lux will give the United States an early and decisive advantage in deploying frontier AI capabilities that transform the pace and scale of scientific innovation. By dramatically expanding the nation’s capacity for scientific AI, Lux strengthens U.S. leadership, accelerates AI-for-Science, and helps ensure that the breakthroughs of the AI era are discovered, developed, and deployed in America. Lux will unleash a new generation of scientific capabilities across the DOE’s mission to, reveal nature’s hidden structure, discover breakthrough materials, accelerate energy innovation, transform biology and biosecurity, and advance national security and resilience. Discovery: America’s Next Leap in Scientific Computing Purpose‑built for AI and science, Discovery features a “Bandwidth Everywhere” design that allows science and AI applications to run efficiently and deliver productive results. Importantly, Frontier laid the foundation for this work, and together with HPE Cray Supercomputing GX5000 – its next-generation supercomputing platform – Discovery builds on that success with a consistent programming environment to ensure an easy transition for users. Discovery will be the DOE’s next flagship supercomputer at ORNL, arriving in 2028, and will extend U.S. leadership in HPC and AI. Advancing America’s innovation agenda, Discovery reflects a strong, public‑private commitment to keep the United States at the forefront of AI and scientific innovation. Building on the breakthroughs of Frontier—the world’s first exascale system—Discovery is designed to deliver dramatically higher performance, energy efficiency, and AI capabilities. Discovery will drive breakthroughs in energy, biology, advanced materials, national security, and manufacturing innovation. It will help design next-generation reactors, batteries, catalysts, semiconductors, and critical materials. Key Points of Discovery: Bandwidth Everywhere: Impressive memory capacity, node, and global network bandwidth compared to first-generation exascale machines, accelerating science and AI applications. Seamless User Transition: Applications built for Frontier transition seamlessly as Discovery continues the successful programming environment. More Compute, Similar Energy: More AI and scientific output at comparable power costs. Open Standards: Discovery is built on open-source software, open standards, and open science to provide the foundation for AI sovereignty. ORNL is expected to take delivery of Discovery in 2028, with user operations expected in 2029. Once online, Discovery will serve as a cornerstone of the American AI Stack, advancing the science, security, and innovation goals that define the nation’s next decade. About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. Cautionary Statement This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) such as features, functionality, performance, availability, timing and expected benefits of AMD products; deployment of AMD technology to power Lux AI supercomputer and timing and expected benefits thereof; and deployment of AMD Instinct™ MI430X accelerators to power the Discovery supercomputer and timing and expected benefits thereof, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as "would," "may," "expects," "believes," "plans," "intends," "projects" and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and generally beyond AMD's control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD’s ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD's ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD's products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD's ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD's reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD's reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors' support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD's supply chain; AMD's ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, tariffs and trade protection measures, and licensing requirements; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes, the revolving credit agreement and the ZT Systems credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; AMD’s ability to complete the sale of ZT Systems’ manufacturing business; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain qualified personnel; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. Oracle Future Product Disclaimer The preceding is intended to outline our general product direction. It is intended for information purposes only, and may not be incorporated into any contract. It is not a commitment to deliver any material, code, or functionality, and should not be relied upon in making purchasing decisions. The development, release, timing, and pricing of any features or functionality described for Oracle’s products may change and remains at the sole discretion of Oracle Corporation. Oracle Forward-Looking Statements Disclaimer Statements in this article relating to Oracle’s future plans, expectations, beliefs, and intentions are “forward-looking statements” and are subject to material risks and uncertainties. Many factors could affect Oracle’s current expectations and actual results, and could cause actual results to differ materially. A discussion of such factors and other risks that affect Oracle’s business is contained in Oracle’s Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) filings, including Oracle’s most recent reports on Form 10-K and Form 10-Q under the heading “Risk Factors.” These filings are available on the SEC’s website or on Oracle’s website at oracle.com/investor. All information in this article is current as of October 27, 2025 and Oracle undertakes no duty to update any statement in light of new information or future events. Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1264/amd-powers-u-s-sovereign-ai-factory-supercomputers-accelerating-an-open-american-ai-stack</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Completes Divestiture of ZT Systems Data Center Infrastructure Manufacturing Business to Sanmina</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1263/amd-completes-divestiture-of-zt-systems-data-center-infrastructuremanufacturing-business-to-sanmina</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights AMD retains ZT Systems’ rack-scale AI solutions design and customer enablement expertise Strategic partnership with Sanmina to accelerate quality and time-to-deployment for cloud customers SANTA CLARA, Calif., Oct. 27, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) today announced the completion of the agreement to divest the ZT Systems U.S.-headquartered data center infrastructure manufacturing business to Sanmina (NASDAQ: SANM). As part of the transaction, AMD retains ZT Systems’ world-class design and customer enablement teams to accelerate the quality and time-to-deployment of AMD AI systems for cloud customers. Additionally, Sanmina becomes a preferred new product introduction (NPI) manufacturing partner for AMD cloud rack and cluster-scale AI solutions to further strengthen the AMD ecosystem of ODM and OEM partners. “Rack-scale innovation marks the next chapter in the AMD data center strategy,” said Forrest Norrod, executive vice president and general manager, Data Center Solutions business unit at AMD. “By extending our leadership from silicon to software to full systems, we’re giving cloud and AI customers an open, scalable path to deploy AMD performance faster than ever. Our strategic partnership with Sanmina brings U.S.-based manufacturing strength together with AMD AI systems design and enablement expertise to deliver quality, speed and flexibility at scale.” About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. Cautionary Statement The statements in this press release include forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (“AMD”), ZT Group Int’l, Inc (“ZT Systems”) and Sanmina Corporation (“Sanmina”), the transaction described herein and other matters. Forward-looking statements may discuss goals, intentions and expectations as to future plans, trends, events, results of operations or financial condition, or otherwise, based on current beliefs and involve numerous risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from expectations. Forward-looking statements speak only as of the date they are made or as of the dates indicated in the statements and should not be relied upon as predictions of future events, as there can be no assurance that the events or circumstances reflected in these statements will be achieved or will occur. Forward-looking statements can often, but not always, be identified by the use of forward-looking terminology including “believes,” “expects,” “may,” “will,” “should,” “seeks,” “intends,” “plans,” “pro forma,” “estimates,” “anticipates,” “designed,” or the negative of these words and phrases, other variations of these words and phrases or comparable terminology. The forward-looking statements in this press release relate to, among other things, the expected benefits and results from AMD’s strategic partnership with Sanmina; AMD’s ability to accelerate the quality and time-to-deployment of AMD AI systems for cloud customers and other expected benefits from the transaction. These forward-looking statements involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from those contemplated by the statements. These risks include, among other things: the failure for such preferred strategic partnership to achieve its anticipated results; failure to accelerate the quality and time-to-deployment of AMD AI systems with ZT Systems design and customer enablement teams; the risks that AMD will not realize expected benefits from the transaction or may take longer to realize than expected; the potential impact of the consummation of the transaction of AMD’s relationships with suppliers, customers, employees and regulators; and demand for AMD’s products. For a discussion of factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from those contemplated by forward-looking statements, see the section captioned “Risk Factors” in AMD’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended December 28, 2024, subsequent Quarterly Reports on Form 10-Q and other filings with the SEC. While the list of factors presented here is considered representative, no such list should be considered to be a complete statement of all potential risks and uncertainties. Unlisted factors may present significant additional obstacles to the realization of forward-looking statements. AMD does not assume, and hereby disclaims, any obligation to update forward-looking statements, except as may be required by law. Contacts: Brandi Martina AMD Communications 512-705-1720 brandi.martina@amd.com Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations (720) 652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1263/amd-completes-divestiture-of-zt-systems-data-center-infrastructuremanufacturing-business-to-sanmina</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD to Participate in Upcoming Investor Conferences</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1262/amd-to-participate-in-upcoming-investor-conferences</link>
      <description><![CDATA[SANTA CLARA, Calif., Oct. 16, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) announced today that company executives will participate in the following events for the financial community: Dr. Lisa Su, chair and chief executive officer, will present at UBS’s 2025 Global Technology and AI Conference on Wednesday, Dec. 3, 2025. Jean Hu, executive vice president, chief financial officer and treasurer, will present at Barclay’s 2025 Global Technology Conference on Wednesday, Dec. 10, 2025. Interested parties are invited to listen to the live webcasts and replays via the AMD Investor Relations website ir.amd.com . About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. AMD, the AMD Arrow logo and the combination thereof are trademarks of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. Other names are for informational purposes only and may be trademarks of their respective owners. Contact Phil Hughes AMD Communications 512-865-9697 phil.hughes@amd.com Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations (720) 652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1262/amd-to-participate-in-upcoming-investor-conferences</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD Showcases “Helios” Rack-Scale Platform Built on the Open Compute Project Open Rack for AI, Introduced by Meta</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1261/amd-showcases-helios-rack-scale-platform-built-on-the-open-compute-project-open-rack-for-ai-introduced-by-meta</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights: At OCP Global Summit 2025, AMD showcased its “Helios” rack-scale design, an open-based AI reference platform aligned with the new Open Rack Wide (ORW) standard contributed to OCP by Meta Powered by AMD Instinct™ GPUs, EPYC™ CPUs and AMD Pensando™ advanced networking, “Helios” will deliver the performance, efficiency, and scalability needed for next-generation AI workloads. "Helios" underscores the focus from AMD to build the infrastructure needed to meet the world’s growing AI demands. SANTA CLARA, Calif., Oct. 14, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Today at the Open Compute Project (OCP) Global Summit in San Jose, AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) showcased a static display of its “Helios,” rack scale platform for the first time in public. Developed based on the new Open Rack Wide (ORW) specification, introduced by Meta, “Helios” extends the AMD open hardware philosophy from silicon to system to rack, representing a major step forward in open, interoperable AI infrastructure. Extending AMD leadership in AI and high-performance computing, “Helios” provides the foundation to deliver the open, scalable infrastructure that will power the world’s growing AI demands. Designed to meet the demands of gigawatt-scale data centers, the new ORW specification defines an open, double-wide rack optimized for the power, cooling, and serviceability needs of next-generation AI systems. By adopting ORW and OCP standards, “Helios” provides the industry with a unified, standards-based foundation to develop and deploy efficient, high-performance AI infrastructure at scale. “Open collaboration is key to scaling AI efficiently,” said Forrest Norrod, executive vice president and general manager, Data Center Solutions Group, AMD. “With ‘Helios,’ we’re turning open standards into real, deployable systems — combining AMD Instinct GPUs, EPYC CPUs, and open fabrics to give the industry a flexible, high-performance platform built for the next generation of AI workloads.” Built for Open, Efficient, and Sustainable AI Infrastructure The AMD “Helios” rack scale platform integrates open compute standards including OCP DC-MHS, UALink, and Ultra Ethernet Consortium (UEC) architectures, supporting both open scale-up and scale-out fabrics. The rack features quick-disconnect liquid cooling for sustained thermal performance, a double-wide layout for improved serviceability, and standards-based Ethernet for multi-path resiliency. As a reference design, “Helios” enables OEMs, ODMs, and hyperscalers to adopt, extend, and customize open AI systems quickly — reducing deployment time, improving interoperability, and supporting efficient scaling for AI and HPC workloads. The Helios platform reflects the ongoing collaboration from AMD across the OCP community to enable open, scalable infrastructure for AI deployments worldwide. You can read more about “Helios” in our blog here and more about the other contributions to OCP from AMD here . Supporting Resources Learn more about AMD AI Solutions Follow AMD on LinkedIn Follow AMD on X About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. CAUTIONARY STATEMENT This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) such as the features, functionality, performance, availability, timing and expected benefits of AMD products including the AMD “Helios” rack scale platform, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as "would," "may," "expects," "believes," "plans," "intends," "projects" and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and generally beyond AMD's control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD’s ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD's ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD's products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD's ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD's reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD's reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors' support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD's supply chain; AMD's ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, tariffs and trade protection measures, and licensing requirements; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes, the revolving credit agreement and the ZT Systems credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; AMD’s ability to complete the sale of ZT Systems’ manufacturing business; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain qualified personnel; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1261/amd-showcases-helios-rack-scale-platform-built-on-the-open-compute-project-open-rack-for-ai-introduced-by-meta</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD and OpenAI Announce Strategic Partnership to Deploy 6 Gigawatts of AMD GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1260/amd-and-openai-announce-strategic-partnership-to-deploy-6-gigawatts-of-amd-gpus</link>
      <description><![CDATA[News Highlights OpenAI to deploy 6 gigawatts of AMD GPUs based on a multi-year, multi-generation agreement Initial 1 gigawatt OpenAI deployment of AMD Instinct ™ MI450 Series GPUs starting in 2H 2026 SANTA CLARA, Calif., Oct. 06, 2025 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) and OpenAI today announced a 6 gigawatt agreement to power OpenAI’s next-generation AI infrastructure across multiple generations of AMD Instinct GPUs. The first 1 gigawatt deployment of AMD Instinct MI450 GPUs is set to begin in the second half of 2026. AMD’s strong leadership in high-performance computing systems and OpenAI's pioneering research and advancements in generative AI places the two companies at the forefront of this important and pivotal time for AI. Under this definitive agreement, OpenAI will work with AMD as a core strategic compute partner to drive large-scale deployments of AMD technology starting with the AMD Instinct MI450 series and rack-scale AI solutions and extending to future generations. By sharing technical expertise to optimize their product roadmaps, AMD and OpenAI are deepening their multi-generational hardware and software collaboration that began with the MI300X and continued with the MI350X series. This partnership creates a true win-win for both companies, enabling very large-scale AI deployments and advancing the entire ecosystem. As part of the agreement, to further align strategic interests, AMD has issued OpenAI a warrant for up to 160 million shares of AMD common stock, structured to vest as specific milestones are achieved. The first tranche vests with the initial 1 gigawatt deployment, with additional tranches vesting as purchases scale up to 6 gigawatts. Vesting is further tied to AMD achieving certain share-price targets and to OpenAI achieving the technical and commercial milestones required to enable AMD deployments at scale. "We are thrilled to partner with OpenAI to deliver AI compute at massive scale," said Dr. Lisa Su, chair and CEO, AMD. "This partnership brings the best of AMD and OpenAI together to create a true win-win enabling the world’s most ambitious AI buildout and advancing the entire AI ecosystem." “This partnership is a major step in building the compute capacity needed to realize AI’s full potential,” said Sam Altman, co-founder and CEO of OpenAI. “AMD’s leadership in high-performance chips will enable us to accelerate progress and bring the benefits of advanced AI to everyone faster.” “Building the future of AI requires deep collaboration across every layer of the stack,” said Greg Brockman, co-founder and president of OpenAI. “Working alongside AMD will allow us to scale to deliver AI tools that benefit people everywhere.” “Our partnership with OpenAI is expected to deliver tens of billions of dollars in revenue for AMD while accelerating OpenAI’s AI infrastructure buildout,” said Jean Hu, EVP, CFO and treasurer, AMD. “This agreement creates significant strategic alignment and shareholder value for both AMD and OpenAI and is expected to be highly accretive to AMD's non-GAAP earnings-per-share.” Through this partnership, AMD and OpenAI are building the infrastructure to meet the world’s growing AI demands, by combining world-class innovation and execution to accelerate the future of high-performance and AI computing. AMD Teleconference AMD will hold a conference call at 5:00 a.m. PT (8:00 a.m. ET) today to discuss today’s announcement. AMD will provide a real-time audio broadcast of the teleconference on the Investor Relations page of its website at www.amd.com . AMD Third Quarter Financial Results AMD will report fiscal third quarter 2025 financial results on Tuesday, Nov. 4, 2025, after the market close. Management will conduct a conference call to discuss these results at 5:00 p.m. EDT / 2:00 p.m. PDT. Interested parties are invited to listen to the webcast of the conference call via the AMD Investor Relations website ir.amd.com .at www.amd.com . About AMD For more than 55 years AMD has driven innovation in high-performance computing, graphics and visualization technologies. Billions of people, leading Fortune 500 businesses and cutting-edge scientific research institutions around the world rely on AMD technology daily to improve how they live, work and play. AMD employees are focused on building leadership high-performance and adaptive products that push the boundaries of what is possible. For more information about how AMD is enabling today and inspiring tomorrow, visit the AMD (NASDAQ: AMD) website , blog , LinkedIn , Facebook and X pages. About OpenAI OpenAI is an AI research and deployment company. Our mission is to ensure that artificial general intelligence benefits all of humanity. Forward-Looking Statements This press release contains forward-looking statements concerning AMD, such as the anticipated benefits of the strategic partnership with OpenAI; the use of current and future AMD technology for large-scale AI deployments; the multi-generational hardware and software collaboration between the parties; milestone and performance-based value creation; the deployment of six gigawatts of AMD Instinct™ GPUs and timing thereof; expected business performance results; AMD’s outlook on the AI industry and AMD’s ability to accelerate the future of high-performance and AI computing; AMD’s ability to position itself to support robust future growth and drive long-term shareholder value, including the expectation that the partnership will deliver tens of billions of dollars in revenue for AMD, that the agreement creates strategic alignment and shareholder value for the parties, and is expected to be highly accretive to AMD’s non-GAAP earnings-per-share; the availability, timing and expected benefits of AMD products and roadmaps; and the expected demand for AMD products, all of which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Forward-looking statements are commonly identified by words such as “would,” “may,” “expects,” “believes,” “plans,” “intends,” “projects” and other terms with similar meaning. Investors are cautioned that the forward-looking statements in this press release are based on current beliefs, assumptions and expectations, speak only as of the date of this press release and involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations. Such statements are subject to certain known and unknown risks and uncertainties, many of which are difficult to predict and generally beyond AMD’s control, that could cause actual results and other future events to differ materially from those expressed in, or implied or projected by, the forward-looking information and statements. Material factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from current expectations include, without limitation, the following: the impact of changes in economic or business conditions of our partners; new developments in the AI industry; successful execution of the business strategy of AMD and its partners; competitive markets in which AMD’s products are sold; the cyclical nature of the semiconductor industry; market conditions of the industries in which AMD products are sold; AMD’s ability to introduce products on a timely basis with expected features and performance levels; loss of a significant customer; economic and market uncertainty; quarterly and seasonal sales patterns; AMD’s ability to adequately protect its technology or other intellectual property; unfavorable currency exchange rate fluctuations; ability of third party manufacturers to manufacture AMD’s products on a timely basis in sufficient quantities and using competitive technologies; availability of essential equipment, materials, substrates or manufacturing processes; ability to achieve expected manufacturing yields for AMD’s products; AMD’s ability to generate revenue from its semi-custom SoC products; potential security vulnerabilities; potential security incidents including IT outages, data loss, data breaches and cyberattacks; uncertainties involving the ordering and shipment of AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party intellectual property to design and introduce new products; AMD’s reliance on third-party companies for design, manufacture and supply of motherboards, software, memory and other computer platform components; AMD’s reliance on Microsoft and other software vendors’ support to design and develop software to run on AMD’s products; AMD’s reliance on third-party distributors and add-in-board partners; impact of modification or interruption of AMD’s internal business processes and information systems; compatibility of AMD’s products with some or all industry-standard software and hardware; costs related to defective products; efficiency of AMD’s supply chain; AMD’s ability to rely on third party supply-chain logistics functions; AMD’s ability to effectively control sales of its products on the gray market; impact of climate change on AMD’s business; impact of government actions and regulations such as export regulations, tariffs and trade protection measures, and licensing requirements; AMD’s ability to realize its deferred tax assets; potential tax liabilities; current and future claims and litigation; impact of environmental laws, conflict minerals related provisions and other laws or regulations; evolving expectations from governments, investors, customers and other stakeholders regarding corporate responsibility matters; issues related to the responsible use of AI; restrictions imposed by agreements governing AMD’s notes, the guarantees of Xilinx’s notes, the revolving credit agreement and the ZT Systems credit agreement; impact of acquisitions, joint ventures and/or strategic investments on AMD’s business and AMD’s ability to integrate acquired businesses, including ZT Systems; AMD’s ability to complete the sale of ZT Systems’ manufacturing business; impact of any impairment of the combined company’s assets; political, legal and economic risks and natural disasters; future impairments of technology license purchases; AMD’s ability to attract and retain qualified personnel; and AMD’s stock price volatility. Investors are urged to review in detail the risks and uncertainties in AMD’s Securities and Exchange Commission filings, including but not limited to AMD’s most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q. Contacts: Phil Hughes AMD Communications 512-865-9697 phil.hughes@amd.com OpenAI press@OpenAI.com Investor Contact Liz Stine AMD Investor Relations (720) 652-3965 liz.stine@amd.com Source: Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.]]></description>
      <author>AMD</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1260/amd-and-openai-announce-strategic-partnership-to-deploy-6-gigawatts-of-amd-gpus</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
