<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity AI Hub</title>
    <link>https://www.perplexity.ai/hub</link>
    <description>Latest news and updates from Perplexity AI</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:05:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing our Partnership with the United States Government</title>
      <link>https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/announcing-our-partnership-with-the-united-states-government</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[Today, we are announcing a first-of-its-kind partnership with the United States government to bring Perplexity to all federal agencies. Americaâs public servants deserve the most powerful, accurate AI to help them serve our nation. To meet this need, weâre collaborating with the General Services Administration (GSA) to provide our flagship enterprise AI platform to federal employees and servicemembers. Through our partnership, federal agencies can acquire Enterprise Pro for Government via GSAâs Multiple Award Schedule (MAS IT) at essentially no cost for up to 18 months. Weâve also negotiated long-term pricing commitments that ensure Perplexity remains a sustainable AI solution for agencies long into the future. This milestone establishes Perplexity as the first major AI company to enter a direct government-wide contract. Consistent with President Trumpâs AI Action Plan and GSAâs OneGov Strategy , Perplexity is proud to help streamline the way agencies deliver frontier AI capabilities to those who serve. Our products already serve tens of thousands of users across the federal workforce, who rely on Perplexity for everything from accelerating daily tasks to informing decisions of national importance. Now, agencies can bring an enterprise-ready edition of Perplexity to all their users, directly from the source itself. As AI models and product capabilities continue to evolve, weâve heard government users consistently call out for one key element: choice. Agency administrators are wary of trapping their agencies on a single model family or a static universe of informationâand rightfully so, given the risks to mission readiness and compliance. Enterprise Pro for Government offers a comprehensive suite of frontier AI models including Perplexity Sonar, GPT, Claude, and Gemini. These models are empowered with a rich, reliable, and configurable ecosystem of information sources, including Perplexityâs internet-scale knowledge index and each agencyâs own systems. Perplexityâs model-agnostic approach means agencies can choose the best model for the specific task at hand, integrate relevant information, and ensure uninterrupted access to frontier AI even when individual model providers become unavailable or incompatible with agency requirements. Security and compliance are key pillars of government AI adoption. In September 2025, we led the way by making Perplexity the first (and currently only) publicly available AI platform to provide secure-by-default guarantees to all federal users, including users with no subscription or contract. Perplexityâs leadership in security continues with Enterprise Pro for Government, which stands today as one of only two services currently designated by the government for AI Prioritization . Awarded based on objective criteria established by GSA, our AI Prioritization designation demonstrates the strength of our security posture and expedites Perplexityâs FedRAMP authorization process through the cloud-native 20x pathway , enabling agencies to adopt Perplexity with full security and compliance. Perplexity is proud to contribute to Americaâs success. Itâs this success that made our own journey possible, and weâre excited to put Perplexity in the hands of those whose work will propel our nation forward. Please visit our US Government hub to learn more about Perplexityâs federal offerings. Questions about procurement via the Multiple Award Schedule can be directed to the National Customer Service Center at ITCSC@gsa.gov â , or to usgov@perplexity.ai .]]&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/announcing-our-partnership-with-the-united-states-government</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>