<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity AI Hub</title>
    <link>https://www.perplexity.ai/hub</link>
    <description>Latest news and updates from Perplexity AI</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:04:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing our Partnership with the United States Government</title>
      <link>https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/announcing-our-partnership-with-the-united-states-government</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[Today, we are announcing a first-of-its-kind partnership with the United States government to bring Perplexity to all federal agencies. Americaâs public servants deserve the most powerful, accurate AI to help them serve our nation. To meet this need, weâre collaborating with the General Services Administration (GSA) to provide our flagship enterprise AI platform to federal employees and servicemembers. Through our partnership, federal agencies can acquire Enterprise Pro for Government via GSAâs Multiple Award Schedule (MAS IT) at essentially no cost for up to 18 months. Weâve also negotiated long-term pricing commitments that ensure Perplexity remains a sustainable AI solution for agencies long into the future. This milestone establishes Perplexity as the first major AI company to enter a direct government-wide contract. Consistent with President Trumpâs AI Action Plan and GSAâs OneGov Strategy , Perplexity is proud to help streamline the way agencies deliver frontier AI capabilities to those who serve. Our products already serve tens of thousands of users across the federal workforce, who rely on Perplexity for everything from accelerating daily tasks to informing decisions of national importance. Now, agencies can bring an enterprise-ready edition of Perplexity to all their users, directly from the source itself. As AI models and product capabilities continue to evolve, weâve heard government users consistently call out for one key element: choice. Agency administrators are wary of trapping their agencies on a single model family or a static universe of informationâand rightfully so, given the risks to mission readiness and compliance. Enterprise Pro for Government offers a comprehensive suite of frontier AI models including Perplexity Sonar, GPT, Claude, and Gemini. These models are empowered with a rich, reliable, and configurable ecosystem of information sources, including Perplexityâs internet-scale knowledge index and each agencyâs own systems. Perplexityâs model-agnostic approach means agencies can choose the best model for the specific task at hand, integrate relevant information, and ensure uninterrupted access to frontier AI even when individual model providers become unavailable or incompatible with agency requirements. Security and compliance are key pillars of government AI adoption. In September 2025, we led the way by making Perplexity the first (and currently only) publicly available AI platform to provide secure-by-default guarantees to all federal users, including users with no subscription or contract. Perplexityâs leadership in security continues with Enterprise Pro for Government, which stands today as one of only two services currently designated by the government for AI Prioritization . Awarded based on objective criteria established by GSA, our AI Prioritization designation demonstrates the strength of our security posture and expedites Perplexityâs FedRAMP authorization process through the cloud-native 20x pathway , enabling agencies to adopt Perplexity with full security and compliance. Perplexity is proud to contribute to Americaâs success. Itâs this success that made our own journey possible, and weâre excited to put Perplexity in the hands of those whose work will propel our nation forward. Please visit our US Government hub to learn more about Perplexityâs federal offerings. Questions about procurement via the Multiple Award Schedule can be directed to the National Customer Service Center at ITCSC@gsa.gov â , or to usgov@perplexity.ai .]]&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/announcing-our-partnership-with-the-united-states-government</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI at work: getting more done with less hype</title>
      <link>https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/ai-at-work-getting-more-done-with-less-hype</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[Our view of AI is pretty simple: the most powerful application of AI is for it to be useful to people. Thatâs because our founding principle, curiosity, rests on the simple premise that a human superpower will always be asking more questions. In fact, history shows the most successful and transformational people in work and life are always those with the most questions. Whatever your vision for your work and career, every vision begins with a question. So how do we zoom this lofty ideal into your day-to-day workflow? Perplexity launched more than 75 features and products this year, many of which integrate directly into your workflow and help you do more. These include Comet, Comet Assistant, Labs, Spaces, Email Assistant, connectors for apps like Gmail, Notion, Linear, and GitHub, a voice assistant to ask questions and get to work on the go, video and image generation, Enterprise protections, and more. For practical tips on how they actually come together we recently published our Perplexity at Work guide. The bottom line is we suggest using AI at work in three ways: First, AI can help you get rid of distractions to reclaim your focus. Everything starts with more focus. Then, AI can multiply your effectiveness. AI should help you scale everything youâre already good at. And finally AI should deliver results. AI needs to support the real outcomes that matter to you. Block distractions: using AI to reclaim your focus A key advantage of AI is its potential to protect your attention in an era of endless interruptions. Notifications, calendar pop-ups, and administrative tasks eat away at the time you could spend truly solving problems. Persistent context-switchingâjumping between apps, email, and documentsâdrains focus and makes thoughtful work difficult. Perplexity is structured to minimize distractions: Routine tasks (like sorting email, scheduling, or gathering content across platforms) are delegated to your AI assistant. Research, updates, and project summaries are surfaced directly, cutting back on the need to bounce between tabs or apps. Context follows your work, so youâre never forced to reassemble information that should simply be there. By assigning these tasks to Perplexityâs system, you gain uninterrupted time for focused effort. The reduction in micro-interruptions is not a small benefitâitâs foundational for deep, high-quality output. Scale yourself: AI is best when you lead with your own talent After clearing a path to deep work, Perplexity enables you to multiply your effectiveness. Its approach isnât to overrule your expertise; itâs to amplify what you already know and do well, letting you operate on a larger and more strategic scale. Integration is key. Instead of approaching AI as an add-on, Perplexity sits within your regular workflowsâresearch, writing, project management, and communication. You can quickly process complex research, synthesize insights from multiple sources, and produce professional deliverables without splitting your attention across the tools required to create them. Advanced functions such as research agents, content synthesis, and task automation let you: Conduct competitive analysis or gather market intelligence across hundreds of sources without hours of manual effort. Produce client-ready reports, presentations, or summaries by giving the intent and letting Perplexity handle formatting and integration. Manage cross-functional projects with a coherent flow of information, making sure nothing is lost in handoffs or transitions. Your expertise remains in charge, but the scale of your impact grows without demanding extra hours or more resources. Get results: use AI to get more done, faster Ultimately, AI should help you achieve results that matter. This means moving beyond outputs to real, measurable progressâdocuments delivered, sales closed, partnerships formed, strategies clarified, and projects completed efficiently. Perplexity keeps you on track by: Summarizing project histories, feedback, and data for performance reviews or professional growth Supporting personalized outreach and lead generation with timely, relevant intelligence for sales or business development Streamlining project execution, ensuring research, planning, and reporting are both accurate and actionable When routine tasks, research, and summarization are handled, your time is freed for strategic work. You put energy into the activities that lead to career progression or business impact, rather than shuffling information or chasing down small details. AI for every workflow AI earns its place at work when it is practical, accountable, and direct. Whether youâre handling a single meeting, preparing for a product launch, or managing the day-to-day grind, AI should be there in the backgroundâquietly supporting your goals, not adding friction. Great AI should support the way you work, extend your strengths, and help you focus on what matters most. It shouldnât be a gimmick, a distraction, or source of uncertainty. AIâs current best use is to make work easier by taking on repetitive or high-friction tasks, bringing order to scattered information, and helping you get clarity from noise. Instead of being another app to juggle or subscription to maintain, worthwhile AI should feel like a seamless extension of your abilities and priorities. The bar for using AI at work shouldn't be impressive. It should be useful . For practical tips on how to use Perplexity, download our Perplexity at Work guide to see how teams at NVIDIA, Bridgewater, and PayPal are getting real work done.]]&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/ai-at-work-getting-more-done-with-less-hype</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>