<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Really Simple AI</title>
    <link>https://reallysimpleai.blogspot.com/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Latest news from Really Simple AI]]></description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:40:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX Acquires xAI to Build Orbital AI Data Centers</title>
      <link>https://reallysimpleai.blogspot.com/2026/02/spacex-acquires-xai-to-build-orbital-ai.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[SpaceX has acquired xAI in a transformative merger aimed at creating space-based data centers powered by solar energy. The integration combines SpaceX's launch capabilities with xAI's artificial intelligence expertise to address the growing power demands of AI infrastructure while advancing humanity's journey to becoming a multi-planetary civilization. The venture addresses a critical challenge: terrestrial AI data centers consume enormous amounts of electricity and cooling resources that Earth's power grid cannot sustainably support. By relocating compute infrastructure to space, the merged company plans to harness near-constant solar power without the environmental and community costs of ground-based facilities. The ambitious plan involves launching a constellation of one million satellites functioning as orbital data centers. Using Starship's unprecedented launch capacity of 200 tons per flight at hourly intervals, SpaceX aims to deliver millions of tons to orbit annually. This approach could add 100 gigawatts of AI compute capacity each year, with satellites generating 100 kilowatts per ton and requiring minimal maintenance. Within two to three years, space-based AI compute is projected to become the most cost-effective solution available. Supporters view the merger as a strategic masterstroke. SpaceX generates massive real-world data from satellites, communications, and navigation that could supercharge xAI's models. Tight integration could accelerate breakthroughs in autonomous systems and space operations while stabilizing xAI financially through SpaceX's proven revenue streams. This exemplifies vertical integration at its finest: hardware, data, and AI combining to create long-term dominance. Critics, however, see significant risks. The merger blurs boundaries between two controversial companies, amplifying regulatory and antitrust scrutiny. SpaceX's mission-focused engineering culture could clash with experimental AI research, while AI's capital-intensive nature might endanger SpaceX's core space ambitions. Concerns grow about excessive concentration of power, data, and influence under one corporate umbrella—raising questions about oversight and accountability. The initiative builds on SpaceX's Starlink program, with plans extending to lunar manufacturing facilities that could deploy hundreds of terawatts of compute infrastructure into deep space, representing a significant step toward harnessing the Sun's energy while funding permanent bases beyond Earth.]]></description>
      <author>Really Simple AI</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:12:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reallysimpleai.blogspot.com/2026/02/spacex-acquires-xai-to-build-orbital-ai.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenClaw: The Open-Source AI Assistant That Lives on Your Computer</title>
      <link>https://reallysimpleai.blogspot.com/2026/02/openclaw-open-source-ai-assistant-that.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[From weekend hack to 100,000 GitHub stars—here's what makes OpenClaw different from ChatGPT and Claude Two months ago, a developer's weekend project caught fire. What began as "WhatsApp Relay" exploded into a phenomenon, drawing 2 million visitors in a single week and accumulating over 100,000 GitHub stars. After navigating trademark challenges and a community-driven evolution, the project has found its permanent identity: OpenClaw. The Name That Stuck The journey to "OpenClaw" wasn't straightforward. The project started as Clawd—a playful take on "Claude" with a claw—until Anthropic's legal team raised concerns. A 5 AM Discord brainstorm with the community produced Moltbot, inspired by how lobsters shed their shells to grow. Meaningful, perhaps, but it never quite rolled off the tongue. OpenClaw represents both the project's open-source DNA and its crustacean heritage. This time, the team did their homework: trademark searches cleared, domains purchased, migration code written. What Makes OpenClaw Different Here's an easy-to-understand breakdown of what it is and how to use it. What It Is Think of OpenClaw as a digital butler that lives on your own computer. Unlike ChatGPT or Claude, which are just chat windows on a website, OpenClaw is software that you install. It uses those smart AI brains (like Claude or Gemini), but it gives them "hands." This means it can actually do things on your computer—like opening files, sending emails, checking your calendar, or controlling smart home lights—rather than just talking about them. How It Works on Your Device It acts as a bridge (or a "gateway") between three things: The Brain: An AI model (you usually plug in an API key from Anthropic, OpenAI, or Google). The Hands: Tools on your computer (it can read files, run programs, or browse the web). The Mouth/Ears: Your chat apps (WhatsApp, Telegram, Discord, etc.). It runs quietly in the background, waiting for you to send it a message. When you ask it to "Summarize the PDF on my desktop," it uses its "hands" to find the file, its "brain" to read it, and its "mouth" to text you the summary. What the Setup Looks Like This is currently the trickiest part for non-technical users, as it is still very new. The Process: It does not yet have a simple "Download and Install" button like a normal app. You currently have to open a Terminal (a text-based command window) and copy-paste a specific command line script to install it. The Wizard: Once the script runs, a "wizard" (a step-by-step text guide) appears in the window. It asks you questions like "Which AI do you want to use?" and "Which chat app do you want to connect?" Security: Because it has control over your computer, the setup includes safety settings so you can limit what it is allowed to touch. How You Can Connect with It Once it is running, you don't usually open the OpenClaw app itself. Instead, you chat with it in your favorite messaging app. Messaging Apps: You can connect it to WhatsApp, Telegram, Discord, Signal, or iMessage. Interaction: You simply open Telegram (for example), find your bot, and text it: "Book me a table for two at 7 PM" or "Remind me to buy milk when I leave work." It replies just like a human friend would. On What It Can Be Run and What Is Preferred Where it runs: It works on macOS (Macs), Windows, and Linux. The Problem: Since it lives on your computer, if your computer goes to sleep or turns off, the "butler" falls asleep too and won't answer you. The Preferred Device: Because of this, users currently prefer to run it on always-on devices. The number one favorite is a Mac Mini—many users leave one running 24/7 as a home server for OpenClaw. Alternatives include a spare laptop that is plugged in and set never to sleep, or a Raspberry Pi (a tiny, cheap computer for hobbyists). What's New in the Latest Release Along with the rebrand, the team has shipped several significant updates. New communication channels now include Twitch and Google Chat plugins. Model support has expanded to include KIMI K2.5 and Xiaomi MiMo-V2-Flash. The web chat interface now supports image sending, matching the functionality available in messaging apps. Security has received particular attention, with 34 security-related commits hardening the codebase. The team has released machine-checkable security models this week and continues working on additional improvements. However, the creator cautions that prompt injection remains an industry-wide unsolved problem, emphasizing the importance of using strong models and studying their security best practices. The Road Ahead Security remains the top priority going forward, alongside gateway reliability and polish. The project is also adding support for more models and providers. The rapid growth has pushed the project beyond what one person can maintain. The creator has been working to add maintainers and establish processes to handle the influx of pull requests and issues. There are also plans to compensate maintainers properly—ideally full-time. The community can help by contributing code or sponsoring the organization. Your Assistant, Your Machine, Your Rules What sets OpenClaw apart from SaaS assistants is control. Your data doesn't live on someone else's servers. OpenClaw runs where you choose—on your laptop, homelab, or VPS. Your infrastructure. Your keys. Your data. As the creator puts it, "The lobster has molted into its final form. Welcome to OpenClaw."]]></description>
      <author>Really Simple AI</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 21:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reallysimpleai.blogspot.com/2026/02/openclaw-open-source-ai-assistant-that.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
